### Ahamad CH

## ahamadch.official@gmail.com

+91 9526092707

# **Professional Summary**

Solution-driven professional excelling in a highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using PHP, Laravel, HTML, CSS, JQuery, and JavaScript. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

## **Experience**

Software Engineer at Axel Technologies Pvt Ltd., Calicut, IN, 9/2017 – Present

Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust web solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance. My responsibilities included debugging and troubleshooting important projects for clients, solving technical issues quickly and accurately with live support.

## Intern at Axel Technologies Pvt Ltd., Calicut, IN, 8/2017 – 9/2017

Enhanced coding and web development skills during this period and started involving in developing important web applications in collaboration with senior developers. Acquired training in front-end web development essentials including responsive designs, integration of third-party applications within the projects and back-end development skills taking account of the MVC pattern.

#### Intern at Uniq Technologies Pvt Ltd., Coimbatore, IN, 2/2017 – 6/2017

Involved in the training program which helped me to strengthen my base in development and coding and acquired hands-on experience in building base projects.

## **Education**

Anna University, Coimbatore, TN

BE Computer Science and Engineering, May 2017

### Skills

Experience in Project Management, Analytics/Statistics, and Software Engineering. Programming Technologies:

- PHP
- Laravel/Lumen
- JQuery/JavaScript
- SQL

- HTML5
- CSS3

# **Projects**

### **HVAC Flat Rate Application.**

This app is focused specifically on the every-day needs of heating and air conditioning contractors. The app provides HVAC Equipment Sales, Flat Rate Pricing, Service Agreement Management, Dispatching, Scheduling, Invoicing, Customer Management, On-Site Diagnostics and Timesheets all within one, easy-to-use program.

### Blugate

Blugate is an online app used to create virtual addresses to shop and deliver products which provides a full suite of retail logistics services, from warehousing and inventory management to order fulfilment to last-mile delivery. It uses a token system for Parcel Management which uses separate admin and user modules for processing. This application is implemented with Payment Gateway integration for Token Purchase, Map integration for bluPort locations and Admin module for managing Parcels, Plans and Promo Codes.

### **Right Logistics**

Right Logistics Pvt. Ltd. is a privately owned Independent freight forwarder with the concept of providing our customers with a comprehensive partnership, to enhance every aspect of their Forwarding requirement.